These Foreign-only subtitles ver. 2025-08 were created by ZoowlCZ.
[Sindarin] Anirne hene beriad i chên lîn.
[English] She wanted to protect her child.
[Sindarin] Ned Imladris nauthant e le beriathar aen.
[English] She thought in Rivendell you would be safe.
[Quenya] Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
[English] Wake up cruel Redhorn!
[Sindarin] Losto Caradhras, Sedho! Hodo!
[English] Sleep Redhorn, Be still! Lie Still!
[Sindarin] Nuitho i 'Ruith!
[English] Hold your Wrath!
[Quenya] Cuiva nwalca Carnirassë!
[English] Wake up cruel Redhorn!
[Quenya] Nai yarvaxëa rasselya...
[English] May your bloodstained horn...
[Quenya] ...taltuva ñotto-carinnar!
[English] ...fall upon enemy heads!
[Sindarin] Annon Edhellen edro hi ammen!
[English] Gate of the elves, open now for me!
[Sindarin] Fennas Nogothrim, lasto beth lammen.
[English] Doorway of the Dwarf-folk, listen to the word of my tongue.
[Quenya] Ando Eldarinwa...
[English] Gate of elves...
[Quenya] ...a lasta quettanya...
[English] ...listen to my word...
[Quenya] ...fenda casarinwa!
[English] ...threshold of dwarves!
[Sindarin] Mellon.
[English] Friend.
[Sindarin] Mae govannen, Legolas Thranduilion.
[English] Welcome, Legolas son of Thranduil.
[Sindarin] Govannas vîn gwennen le, Haldir o Lórien.
[English] Our fellowship stands in your debt, Haldir of Lórien.
[Sindarin] A Aragorn in Dúnedain...
[English] Oh, Aragorn of the Dúnedain...
[Sindarin] ...istannen le ammen.
[English] ...you are known to us.
[Sindarin] Boe ammen veriad lîn. Andelu i ven!
[English] We need your protection. The road is too dangerous!
[Sindarin] Merin le telim.
[English] I wish we may come with you.
[Sindarin] Boe ammen i dulu lîn!
[English] We need your support!
[Sindarin] Merin le telim.
[English] I wish we may come with you.
[Sindarin] Andelu i ven!
[English] The road is too dangerous!
[Sindarin] Le aphadar aen.
[English] You are being tracked.
[Sindarin] Am meleth dîn...
[English] For her love...
[Sindarin] ...I ant e guil Arwen Undómiel pígatha.
[English] ...the gift of life of Arwen will fade.
[Sindarin] Aníron i e broniatha...
[English] I wish that she endures...
[Sindarin] ...Ad ae periatham athar i methid en-amar hen.
[English] ...even if we separate beyond the limits of this world.
[Sindarin] Aníron i e círatha na Valinor.
[English] I wish that she sails to Valinor.
[Quenya] Namárië.
[English] Farewell.
[Sindarin] Nadath nâ i moe cerich...
[English] There is much you have yet to do...
[Sindarin] ...dan...
[English] ...but...
[Sindarin] ...ú-'eveditham, Elessar.
[English] ...we shall not meet again, Elessar.
[Black Speech] Akha...
[English] Here...
[Black Speech] ...ashi...
[English] ...only...
[Black Speech] ...gurum!
[English] ...death!